Welcome to this video about this task to create
a class diagram with inheritances.
For this task we have been given a little
scenario.
Which we have to consider in order to create
a simple class diagram.
Also, we should think about the properties
that the actors and institutions in this model
must have.
And then, give an appropriate class diagram
with inheritances.
And we also have to define the types of the
attributes.
For this task I want to read the little scenario.
Different persons appear in our model.
The differently aged students, examiners and
the examination office.
Of course, students and examiners are persons.
Every person has a name but only students
have a matriculation number.
Examiners are somewhat sensitive about their
age, so, it should not be stored for them.
Examiners are responsible for a specific course.
So, that course’s name should be stored
for them.
The examination office has a number of employees.
That number, but no further information about
employees needs to be stored in order to distribute
the workload.
Okay so, we can start with the first sentence
which tell us a lot about this class diagram.
It tell us that are different persons in our
model. There are differently aged students.
So, first of all, we have student as a
class.
Then, we have examiners.
And we have the examination office.
We write those classes in Camel Case which
means that the first letters are uppercase letters
and all the other letters are lowercase.
But if we have a word which consist in multiple
words.
Then, we use a capital letter for every starting
letter of a word and leave the spaces out.
So, like we did here with the examination
office.
And we use singular forms for our classes.
So, we have the examiner class, the student
class and the examination office.
And we have another class given in the next
sentence.
Where it states that of course students and examiners
are persons.
So, we have another class called “person”.
And there it states that every person has a
name.
But only students have matriculation numbers.
So, we have the name for the persons.
And for students we have the matriculation
number.
Okay, and this was the information about the
persons.
But we also have info about the students which
was that they are aged.
So, we also have the age for the students.
And now, we have the examiners and they do not
have their ages stored.
This is important.
Because if they would have the age then we
would have to define the age within Person.
But the ages are only stored for the students,
so we don’t store the age for the examiners.
And the examiners are responsible for a specific
course.
So, we should store the course name.
I have written the matriculation number and
age as “Int” here.
Because I think it should be quite clear that
the age is of course an Int value.
And the matriculation number is usually an
Int.
So, we have it in Duisburg-Essen as well.
So, we use just an Int value here and the
name it’s of course “String” and we
have the course now here for the examiner.
And this is the name of the course.
So, obviously it should be “String” as
well.
So, we define the course for the examiner.
And the examination office has the number
of employees.
So, as we talk about a number, we
should use “Int” as a type here.
So, we can say, the examination office has
the number of employees as Int so we can call it,
for instance, “employees” and say there is
an Int value for that.
There’s no further information stored about
the employees.
So, we just have this number.
And that’s everything besides the inheritances
that are required.
And this information, we get from the sentence
that students and examiners are persons.
This implies that we should have an inheritance
here.
So, students should inherit from Person.
But also, the examiners.
So, we can draw an inheritance to Person
from both of them.
And now we got the whole diagram for this
task.